KOONI
（酷妮）
I want this character.
我想要这个角色
Let me verify your age.
让我核实一下你的年龄
Are you 18 or older?
你年满18岁了吗？
Yes.
是的
You'll get into trouble
你之后会有
later on.
麻烦
FREE LEGAL CONSULTATION
（免费法律咨询）
So, we hold events like this too.
也会举办这样的活动啊
Yes. So that people can reach out easily.
对 这样方便大家找上门
One-hour consultation is free. There's a fee for those with requests--
前一小时的咨询免费 一旦要委托了才确认费用…
Man, this is such a hassle.
老天 真麻烦
It's because you're not getting any cases.
那是因为你接不到案子
We have renovation loans, utility costs and also your salary--
我们要付装修贷款 水电费之类的 还有你的工资…
I got it.
明白了
There you go again.
怎么又来了
Hey, hey.
嘿
What?
怎么？
We start at 11 o'clock.
11点才能开始
It's only a banner.
只是挂个横幅而已
It would look like we're already open.
这样看起来我们好像已经开张了
It's only one or two more minutes.
一两分钟就别计较了
No!
不行
I'll leave it to you then, Ishiko.
那就交给你了 石子小姐
You came to a tough workplace.
你来到了很辛苦的职场啊
No. They let me work part-time while I look for a job. I'm only grateful.
不会 在找工作的时候让我来打工 我感激不尽
Good boy.
好孩子
I expect your paychecks' worth of performance.
为了挣工资 请你好好工作吧
You got it.
没问题
"When coming up with genius ideas, I should furrow my eyebrows."
“想到天才点子时皱紧眉头”
He's at it again.
又来了
Did you bring your phone?
你带手机了吗？
Excuse me, are you open?
不好意思 请问开始了吗？
Yes.
是的
I'd be happy to consult you.
我很乐意咨询你
Um, my son paid for game items without telling me.
我儿子瞒着我在游戏里充值了
Can you help us?
有什么解决办法吗？
Alright, let me confirm.
好吧 让我确认一下
Ms. Eiko Aida, you let Kota, your sixth-grader son, have a smartphone.
相田瑛子女士 让小学六年级的儿子孝多用智能手机
But only to contact him,
但只是为了跟他联系
who attends cram school until late every night.
因为孝多每天晚上都补习到很晚
However, Kota bought 198,700 yen worth of items for a social game called
然而孝多在社交游戏里 充值十九万八千七百日圆
Dropping Puzzle, also known as Doropazu without your permission.
这个游戏名叫《扔谜语》 简称《扔谜》
You found this out three days ago,
你在三天前看到信用卡账单时
when you checked your credit card statement.
发现了这件事
You tried to cancel it, but it had already been withdrawn.
虽然立刻向信用卡公司取消 但金额已经扣款
You sent a refund request mail to Tension, the company that manages Doropazu,
因此你致信管理此游戏的腾信公司 要求退款
but they declined your request and that's why you're here.
但对方回复无法退款 你们因此无计可施
This is his smartphone. And Doropazu… There it is.
这是他的手机 然后《扔谜》…是这个
Yes.
对的
It looks fun.
看起来很好玩
Right?
对吧？
Kota.
孝多
Sorry.
对不起
May I look through your phone?
我可以仔细看下手机吗？
Oh, yes. Of course.
当然可以
Apparently, he can memorize what he sees like a photograph.
他可以像拍照一样 把看到的东西都记下来
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样？
Well, we'll probably have to talk to their legal department or lawyer.
可能必须跟对方的法务 或顾问律师谈过
But Article 5 of the Civil Code states that a contract made by a minor
不过民法第五条规定 未成年人未经父母同意
without parental consent can be rescinded.
所订定的契约是可以取消的
Leave it to me.
我来处理吧
Oh, thank you very much!
感激不尽
Kota, I wasn't sure but I'm so glad we decided to come.
孝多 我原本还不确定 幸好来咨询了
And do we have to go to court?
请问 接下来需要上法庭吗？
Legal fees cost a lot, right?
诉讼费用会很高 对吧？
No, it should be fine. I'm sure they wouldn't want that either.
不用担心 对方应该也不想要上法庭
That's great.
太好了
Excuse me.
不好意思
It feels wrong to rescind just because a child did it.
因为是小孩子做的就能取消 感觉不太对吧
Ah, I know what you mean.
我懂你的意思
But it's a rule that a minor's mistakes should be covered by society.
但未成年的过失要由社会来承担 这是法律的原则
-Ishiko, the contract. -Coming.
-石子小姐 说一下合约 -来了
Now, this is our fee.
跟你说明一下费用
Really, I'm fine by myself.
我自己真的没问题
No. I'm worried about your actions that lack L.E.
不 我是担心你缺乏律伦的行为
L.E.?
律伦？
Lawyer Ethics.
律师伦理
-Go home. -No way.
-回去 -没办法
-Mr. Haneoka. -Oh, hi.
-羽根冈律师 -好久不见
How are you?
你好吗？
I didn't think you were the legal counsel.
没想到你们是那间公司的法律顾问
I'm sorry I resigned so suddenly.
当初突然离职 不好意思
Not a problem.
没关系
I've been wondering how you've been after you quit.
一直很好奇你离职后的情况
But I'm happy for you.
不过真为你高兴
They insisted on having me in their firm.
他们不管怎样都想邀请我过去
That's right. We needed him.
没错 我们非常希望他能来
Is that so?
这样子吗？
Here's the access log to the account you requested.
这是你们要求的账号访问记录
There've been payments repeatedly, so it's clear that these are not mistakes.
因为有多次充值的记录 很明显并没有过失
However, the user is currently 12 years old.
可是 使用者现在才12岁
The minor's right to rescind--
根据限制行为能力人的解约权…
But since the phone is under the mother's name,
但是手机是用妈妈的名字办的
we have no proof that it was used by a minor.
没有证据能确认是未成年人在使用
Unless you can prove--
除非你能证明…
So, you'll give us the refund if we can prove that. Correct?
所以只要能证明 你们就愿意退款 对吧？
We're gathering the records--
我们正在收集必要的记录…
Mr. Haneoka.
羽根冈律师
Here's the problem.
问题是…
Doropazu asks if you're 18 years or older
《扔谜》会让用户确认 其是否年满18岁
and only users who select "Yes" can pay for game items.
只有回答“是”才有办法充值
Meaning, he lied that he's an adult.
换句话说 是使用者谎称自己已成年
This is fraud clearly intended to deceive the game operators--
这是明显意图欺瞒游戏业者的欺诈…
Under METI standards,
根据经济产业省的标准
even if a minor chose "Yes" to "Are you an adult?" it's not a fraud--
询问“是否已成年”时 未成年人回答“是”也不构成欺诈
Mr. Haneoka, Doropazu asks if the user is 18 years or older.
羽根冈律师 游戏问的是 使用者“是否已经年满18岁”
I know that.
这点我知道
But this April, the legal adult age was lowered to 18.
不过从今年四月开始 法定成年年龄已经降低到18岁
So, asking if you're 18 or older…
因此“是否已经年满18岁”
-Mr. Haneoka! -It's the same as--
-羽根冈律师 -意思就是…
Then…
那么…
I guess we'll just have to settle this in court.
只能上法庭解决了吧
If it's approved, the refund will be paid.
法院同意的话 我们就退款
-But a trial is-- -Then…
-但是庭审… -那么…
You'll just have to give up.
你们只能放弃了
I've heard your story.
我听说了
After you got kicked out of our company, no one wanted to hire you, right?
你被我们踢出去之后 没有其他律所想雇用你吧？
Can someone like that
像你这样的人
turn this case over?
有办法翻案吗？
I'll see you in court.
那就法庭上见
Geez, he's trying to rattle me with such a lie.
哎呀 为了让我动摇 竟然说出那样的谎话
You don't believe him, right?
你不会相信他吧？
Right.
不会
I almost fell for it.
真是受不了
GET INTO KEIMEI MIDDLE SCHOOL
（考上经明中学）
SCHOOL SELECTION TEST (SAT)
（志愿学校排名测验）
MOCK EXAM
（实力模拟考）
I see.
原来是这样
It's my fault too. I've been busy with work
我也有错
and I didn't have things under control.
一直忙于工作 没有管好他
You must be very busy.
你一定很忙吧
I'm a single parent. So, you know.
单亲家庭总是状况比较多
Middle school entrance exam?
要考中学啊？
Oh, I wasn't really thinking about it,
我其实没那么在意
but he said he wants to go to a good school and take care of me in the future.
但这孩子说他想上好学校 将来才能照顾我
Kids grow up so fast before you know it.
孩子真的是在你不知不觉间就长大了
So Mr. Haneoka,
羽根律师
does this mean we're going to court?
意思是要上法庭了吗？
Um, not exactly--
也不是…
I don't want to take the exam.
我不想考了
I want to quit cram school.
补习学校我也不想去了
I've had enough.
我已经受够了
That's why I've been playing games.
我就是不想考试才一直玩游戏
Please excuse us.
不好意思
What are you saying?
怎么突然说这些？
You're lying, right?
这不是真的吧？
I'm not.
我是说真的
You're lying.
你一定在说谎
I won't approve of this.
我不会同意的
Kota, what's going on?
孝多 发生了什么事？
Kota.
孝多
Kota, look at me.
孝多 看着我
Um, I'm really sorry about this.
真的很不好意思
I wonder if he really said he wants to take the exam.
他真的说过想要考试吗？
It seemed like his mother was imposing her wishes on him.
看起来是妈妈把自己的愿望 强加在他身上
Like a toxic parent?
你是说她像是毒亲吗？
I guess.
可以这么说
Even if she is, it has nothing to do with this case.
即使如此 也跟这次的案件无关
-Is that a game? -What?
-你在玩游戏吗？ -什么？
No, it's part of my job. I'm checking out Doropazu.
不是 这是工作的一部分 我在确认游戏的内容
It might help me with the case.
这能帮助我了解案情
It only seems like a waste of time.
在我看来只是在浪费时间
That's not true.
才不是这样
I also think it's a waste of time to practice furrowing your eyebrows.
练习皱眉也只是在浪费时间
-You saw my memo. -Memo?
-你看了我的笔记？ -笔记？
I'm trying to keep our firm out of trouble.
这是为了防止你造成律所的麻烦
-What memo? -We lawyers have our own issues.
-什么笔记？ -律师也是要考量很多事的
Don't think of him as the average lawyer.
不要把他当成标准的律师
Because I'm above average.
她的意思是我比一般的律师还厉害
No!
才不是
I mean his concept of the norm isn't average. Get to work.
我的意思是 他的规范概念 并不在标准内 快去工作
Yes.
是
And he has the tendency to exaggerate himself. Beware of that.
此外 他夸大了自己的倾向 请小心
On what basis is she saying this?
她说这种话有什么根据？
Your social media. Your lunch the day before yesterday.
你的社交网站 前天的午餐
It says, "I'm having a hotdog at a park between meetings. So busy!"
你说：“我太忙了 趁会议的空档 在公园吃热狗”
But in fact, you were slurping noodles right here in the office.
事实上你根本就在律所里 无所事事地吃拉面
This is called hype marketing.
这就叫做不实广告
No way!
才不是！
You're steel-headed, Ms. Tetsuko.
你的脑筋很死呢 铁子小姐
Tetsuko?
铁子？
As in steel, harder than stone.
比石头还硬 所以叫你铁子
What a load of nonsense, Mr. Morio.
你讲太多废话了 吹男先生
Morio?
吹男？
Morio, as in "More exaggeration than truth."
讲话夸大吹牛的男人 吹男
You're the one spewing nonsense.
你真是无理取闹
Let's stop this.
不要吵了吧
Whose side are you on? You think Tetsuko is right?
你支持哪一边？ 你觉得铁子小姐是对的吗？
Or Morio?
还是要支持吹男先生？
Which is it?
请选择
Who knows at what temperature water turns into ice?
谁知道水结冰的温度？
Me!
我
Okay, Yamazaki.
山崎同学
It's 0℃.
零度
If someone passes, that means someone else fails.
有人上榜 就代表有人落榜
Do you want to fail?
你们想落榜吗？
No, sir!
不想
You want to pass?
你们想上榜吧？
Yes, sir!
想
You want to win?
你们想赢吧？
Wow.
哇
Who else knew that the answer is one-third?
还有人知道答案是1/3吗？
Me.
我
Open page 53 of your textbook.
翻到教材53页
Good job everyone.
大家辛苦了
The next class is…
下一堂课是…
Don't go outside of this building.
不要跑到大楼外面
Come back in 15 minutes.
15分钟后回来上课
Excuse me, who are you?
请问 你们是谁？
This is it for today. Good job everyone.
今天就上到这里 大家辛苦了
Thank you.
谢谢老师
Man, it's so tiring.
老天 累死人了
Oh, Kota.
孝多
Yes.
是
Go ahead.
过来一下
Who's that?
谁啊？
A lawyer.
律师
His mother asked us for help.
他妈妈请我们帮忙
About what?
帮什么忙？
-No details. -About that game.
-具体细节不方便谈 -游戏的事
If you're a lawyer, are you smart?
你是律师 一定很聪明吧？
Yes, I am smart.
我很聪明
-Which university? -I went to university abroad.
-上哪所大学？ -我是读国外的大学
So cool.
好酷
But I dropped out because I didn't see the point.
不过我觉得没意义 就休学了
What? So, you're a high school graduate?
什么？所以你只是中学毕业？
Well, yeah.
这个嘛 对
What about you?
你呢？
The University of Tokyo.
东京大学
-Really? -Amazing!
-这样啊？ -太厉害了
-Yes. -You're very blatant.
-是 -你也表现得太露骨了吧
I have to go. Bye, Miss.
我得走了 姐姐再见
-Bye. -Goodbye.
-拜拜 -再见
I wish I was born into a good family like Eiichi.
真希望能像荣一那样出生在好人家
But he comes from a family of doctors, so the pressure is intense.
但他家是医师世家 压力也是很大的
Yeah, but he's already a winner if he's that rich.
即使如此 他家那么有钱 已经是人生赢家了
I totally lost the parent-gacha.
我的父母转蛋真的运气很差
Parent-gacha…
父母转蛋…
See you. Miss, goodbye.
姐姐再见 我先走了
So, they all refuse to greet me.
都没跟我打招呼
-To the main topic. -Yes.
-言归正传吧 -是
This is your Doropazu access log.
这是你的游戏访问记录
According to this, you play twice a week on average.
根据记录 你平均一星期玩两次
That's only seven times a month.
一个月只玩七次
It seems you played very little considering you were so addicted
以你上瘾到 充值十九万八千七百日圆来说
that you spent 198,700 yen.
玩游戏的频率有点太少了
Busted.
被你发现了
Actually, I'm not really into it.
事实上我不是很入迷
But I did it to let my mom know that I don't want to take the exam.
只是想让妈妈知道我不想考试才玩的
I remembered there was someone who was
我记得有人太沉迷于游戏
forced by their parents to quit cram school because of a video game.
爸妈就叫他不要来补习班了
So, you paid for game items on purpose?
所以你是故意充值？
That's terrible. You've deceived a lot of people.
太过分了 你欺骗了很多人
Let's tell your mother the truth.
跟你妈妈说实话吧
Okay. I'll tell her, but give me some time.
好 我会告诉她 再等我一下
I wonder if he thought his mom won't let him quit unless he did all that.
他应该是认为不这样做 妈妈不会让他退掉补习班吧
Like I said, it's not our business.
我已经说了 这不关我们的事
I wonder if any of it is actually the children's choice.
考中学这件事 有多少是他自己的选择呢？
When I was in sixth grade, having fun and Kendo was all I did.
小学六年级时 我满脑子只有玩耍和剑道
How innocent.
真是天真无邪
Really?
是吗？
Did you think about taking exams?
你想过要考试吗？
I took the middle school entrance exam.
我考中学了啊
For real? So, you worked hard like Kota?
真的吗？ 你也像孝多一样拼命读书吗？
Nope. I didn't go to cram school and I had no struggles.
没有 我没上补习班 也没特别努力
What?
什么？
I have an extraordinary memory.
我的记忆力特别好
I see.
这样啊
But…
不过…
it's not like I wanted to take it.
我也不是自己想考才去考的
These exams are for your parents' benefit.
考试都是为了爸妈
Has Shoko always been smart?
硝子从小就那么聪明吗？
Yeah. But I divorced her mother when she entered middle school,
是 但她上中学时 我跟她妈就离婚了
so I don't know about after that.
之后的事情我就不太清楚了
She got into University of Tokyo in one try.
她一次就考上东京大学吧
Yeah.
是的
She must've studied so hard.
她一定很用功吧
My ex-wife must've worked really hard for her.
我前妻一定也很努力吧
Mom did, huh?
妈妈吗？
Don't call her mom.
不要叫她妈妈
-Why not? -Just don't.
-有什么关系？ -就是有关系
I only meant I wish I could've met her.
我没别的意思 只是想认识她
Oh, right. Anyway, you should leave.
是吗？你可以回去了
I have time.
我不赶时间
It's not about your schedule.
不是你赶不赶时间的问题
It's mine.
我还有事情要忙
Anyways, the bar exam must be very difficult, huh?
不过司法考试一定很难吧？
A smart girl like Shoko failed four times.
硝子那么聪明还落榜了四次
She'd pass in a few more tries, right?
再考个几次就会通过了吧？
Well, the thing is, you can only take it five times.
问题是 最多只能考五次
What? So next year is her last chance?
什么？所以明年是最后的机会了？
Well, yeah.
对
Aren't you warming it up?
挤在这里不会热吗？
-Hello. -Welcome home.
-你好 -欢迎回来
Hi, Shoko!
你好 硝子
-Hello. -Huh? Who are they?
-你好 -他们是谁？
-I've told you. -What?
-我已经跟你说过了 -什么？
You didn't tell me that they're so good-looking.
你没说他们都是帅哥啊
Why would I say all that?
谁会说得那么详细
He's Mr. Shiozaki, the Soba restaurant owner.
这位是荞麦面店的老板盐崎
-Hi. -Hello.
-请多指教 -你好
Hey.
你好
This is bad.
这下惨了
What is it? What's bad?
在说什么？有什么好惨的？
Thank you.
谢谢惠顾
Thank you. Take care.
谢谢 回去小心
This is so bad.
惨了…
So handsome…
太帅了吧
-I'm sorry. You scared me. -I'm sorry.
-抱歉 我吓到了 -抱歉
I'm terribly sorry. Is Mr. Haneoka here?
真的很抱歉 羽根冈律师在吗？
-You have a guest! -Can we help you?
-有客人 -怎么了吗？
Oh, sorry. I got charged for that game again.
不好意思 我又收到游戏的账单了
TENSION INC. 254,000 YEN
（腾信公司 二十五万四千日圆）
254,000 yen.
二十五万四千日圆
The full credit limit in one day?
一天就到达上限额度？
Yes.
是的
It wasn't me.
不是我
I don't think it's him.
我想应该不是他
Since that billing, I changed the setting so he can't play games on it anymore.
上次账单来了之后 我就设定不能在手机上玩游戏了
I've suspended my credit card,
信用卡也停止使用了
but what should I do?
现在该怎么办才好？
Um, c-can I talk to you?
可以跟你谈一下吗？
Excuse me.
不好意思
Sure.
当然
-Here. -Thank you.
-请用 -不好意思 谢谢
It's really not your doing?
真的不是你做的吧？
No.
不是
I'm Ushio.
我姓潮
That means someone hacked the account and bought the items.
那就是有人盗用帐号充值了
Have you told your mother about that thing?
那件事你跟妈妈说了吗？
Not yet.
还没
It might be hard to talk about, but are you getting bullied?
你或许很难开口 但有人霸凌你吗？
Not at all.
没有
I see. Here.
这样啊 给你
Is it possible your credit card information was leaked?
你的信用卡资料有没有可能泄露？
I doubt that.
应该没有
The password?
密码呢？
I didn't tell anyone.
我没有告诉任何人
Hmm.
嗯
This is a completely different case to the previous billing problem.
这跟先前的充值问题 是完全不同的情况
Unauthorized access and use of a credit card. This is a criminal case.
未经授权使用信用卡 这是刑事案件
Let's talk to the police.
我们报警吧
Please. Regarding the retainer fee, you can bill that to me again.
拜托你们了 聘用费可以另外算
No need. We can deal with it with the initial fee.
不用了 有一开始的聘用费就可以了
-Huh? But… -No.
-什么？可是… -不
It's our job to be the umbrella for those in need.
我们的工作就是 成为有需要之人的保护伞
Right?
对吧？
Thank you so much. You saved me!
感激不尽 真是帮了大忙了
Doropazu again?
又在玩那个游戏了？
It's my break time.
现在是休息时间
You play it during work too.
你上班时间也在玩
Ow…
哎哟…
How do you want to proceed with the initial refund?
一开始的退款案件 你要怎么处理？
As long as our client refuses to go to trial,
委托人拒绝出庭
we're in a bind if the opponent is so defiant.
对方的态度又这么强硬 我们束手无策了
Please don't give up.
请你不要放弃
The police is handling the 250,000 yen. So there's nothing to do.
二十五万日圆的事也交给警方了 现在没我们的事了
There's time until the information is disclosed.
申请资料揭露还需要一段时间
Why don't we investigate someone who has a grudge--
趁现在调查看看有没有人 对瑛子小姐怀恨在心而犯案吧？
Let the police handle it.
交给警方处理吧
Kota, look at me.
孝多 看着妈妈
Good work today. See you tomorrow.
辛苦了 我先走了
JUSTY INC.
（贾思提公司）
She's working two jobs.
她身兼二职啊
Um. Once again, I'm looking forward to working with you.
那个…接下来还请多多指教
Same here.
彼此彼此
I'm job hunting at the same time, so I may cause trouble--
我一边在找工作 或许会带来麻烦…
You're too polite. And a little too loud.
礼貌过头了 而且有点话多
Right, I'm sorry.
不好意思
Let's take it easy.
轻松一点吧
Okay. See you tomorrow.
好 那我先走了
Oh, by the way. Come back here a bit.
对了…回来一下
-Okay, too close. -Sorry.
-太近了 -不好意思
So…
那个…
what do you think about Ishiko?
你对硝子小姐是怎么想的？
Huh?
什么？
Um, she's a senior I respect--
她是我尊敬的学姐…
You like her?
你喜欢她吗？
What?
什么？
Oh. It's not like that.
不是这样的
Well, it doesn't matter really.
其实不重要啦
It's just I'm dense at things like that. So, I thought I'd ask.
只是我对这种事情很迟钝 想说应该要问清楚
It's very… that.
完全没那个意思
-Got it. -Okay.
-了解 -好
Bye.
再见
Goodbye.
辛苦了
Got it.
了解
KAMOGAYA
（鸭谷）
Kota is close friends with Eiichi Kitano.
跟孝多比较好的有北野荣一
Eiichi Kitano.
北野荣一同学
And Emiru Tanaka, I guess.
还有田中绘美瑠吧
Emiru Tanaka.
田中绘美瑠同学
Is there anyone else?
还有其他人吗？
Is Kota alright?
孝多没事吧？
I heard that Kota paid a lot for game items on Doropazu.
听说孝多在《扔谜》大量充值
Hello? Ishida speaking.
你好 我是石田
What do you think you're doing?
你在干什么？
Excuse me?
什么？
We got a complaint about you talking to the students.
有人来投诉 叫你不要去接触学生
I was wondering where you were.
我就在想你跑去哪里了
CRAM SCHOOL BUILD UP
（天天向上补习班）
I was hoping to get a clue to find the culprit.
我只是希望能找到犯人的线索
Any possibility--
可能吗…
I'm not sure, but it's not zero.
不知道 但几率不是零
How inefficient.
真没效率
I don't want to hear it from you who only plays games.
只会玩游戏的人没资格说我
My impression of his mother changed.
我对他妈妈的印象有点改观了
You said she's a toxic parent.
之前不是才说她是毒亲吗？
I haven't reached that conclusion. But…
我没有做出那样的结论 不过…
I want to help her in any way I can.
我想多少帮她一点忙
Right.
对
Hang on. Are you the kind of person who says things like that?
等一下 你是会说这种话的人吗？
I thought you were all about money.
我以为你只对金钱有兴趣
As long as we're getting paid--
毕竟我们收了聘用费…
Anyway, just don't do anything without my instructions.
总之 没有我的指示你不要乱来
You are a paralegal.
你是律师助理
You got it?
知道吗？
Is it okay to get complaints, according to your rules?
接到投诉不会违反你的原则吗？
Hello--
喂…
DROPPING PUZZLE ACCESS LOG
（《扔谜语》访问记录）
My eyes are tired.
眼睛好酸
Ishiko?
石子？
-Oh, hi. -Hello.
-辛苦了
-See you tomorrow. -Wait. Take this.
-明天见 -等等 雨伞给你
-You'll get wet. -I'll be fine.
-你会淋湿的 -我没关系
No, really.
真的不用
Then, why don't we use it together?
那要一起撑吗？
I just remembered I forgot something in the office.
我刚想起有东西忘在律所了
Let's go together.
一起回去吧
Well, if you insist.
那我就不客气了
Okay.
好
Are your shoulders covered?
你的肩膀挡到了吗？
Yes.
没问题
I heard a funny joke the other day.
我前几天听到个很好笑的笑话
Okay.
是
Uh, it's about maternity.
跟母性有关的故事
Maternity?
母性？
Yes.
对
Do you know what kind of tea a pregnant person drinks?
这个有母性的人 把茶洒到大腿上了 然后说
A materni…
这才是真正的…
Oh.
哦
I gave it away…
我说溜嘴了
What?
什么？
No, I…
不是 我…
It's about pregnancy.
是说怀孕
A pregnant person.
那个孕妇
Could you forget I said "maternity"?
可以请你先忘掉“母性”吗？
-I can't. -I thought so.
-没办法 -说得也是
I'm so bad at this.
我真的好没用
You looked down,
看你很沮丧的样子
so I was trying to make you laugh.
才想说要逗你笑
I'm sorry.
结果失败了
I appreciate it.
感激不尽
Huh?
什么？
Thanks to you, I feel a little better.
多亏你 我心情好多了
Really?
这样子吗？
A pregnant woman and a tea.
孕妇把茶水洒在大腿上
Right.
是
-Materni-tea. -Materni-tea, right?
-日语念起来就像“母性” -母性 对吗？
I got it.
我懂了
HANEO I'M A NEWBIE. PLEASE TEACH ME!
（羽男：我是新手 请多指教）
ENMA SURE! YOU SHALL BE ADDICTED TO DOROPAZU.
（恩玛：没问题 好好享受 《扔谜》的魅力吧）
Why do you sound so strange?
这语气听起来怎么怪怪的？
Hot.
好烫
YUNO HANEOKA
（羽根冈优乃）
Let's eat.
我要开动了
Morning.
早
Good morning!
早安
How do you level up?
这个游戏要怎么升级？
-Huh? -Doropazu.
-什么？ -《扔谜》
I started playing too.
我也开始玩了
Right.
是啊
You can defeat enemies.
必须击败敌人
And join events to gain experience points.
多参加活动 累积经验值
It's all about experience, huh?
什么事都需要经验啊？
You're wearing it backward.
你衣服穿反了
Yeah. Um, this is how you wear it.
对 这是我今天的穿搭
My bad, then.
那不好意思
Alright. Let's go meet the culprit.
我们去见真凶吧
What?
什么？
The account hacker.
盗用帐号的黑客
I finally became friends with Kota's character in the game.
我终于跟游戏里孝多的角色交了朋友
"I'm a lawyer representing that account."
“我是那个帐号用户的代理律师
"You're hacking people's accounts and paying for game items illegally."
你盗用他人帐号非法充值
"It's only a matter of time until I get your information and find you."
取得你的信息只是时间早晚的问题”
I sent him that in a DM and got a reply immediately.
传了这样的短信过去之后 对方就立刻回复了
"Help me. I'm being threatened"?
“救救我 我被威胁了吗？”
We're supposed to meet here.
我们约好在这里碰面
So you weren't just playing games.
原来你不是只在玩游戏啊
Of course not. It's all going as planned.
当然 一切都按照计划进行
I'm sorry!
对不起
Huh? You're the hacker?
什么？你就是盗用帐号的人？
So, you paid for the game items. Correct?
你的确充值了 对吧？
Yes.
是的
Didn't you feel guilty towards Kota?
不会对孝多觉得不好意思吗？
That was Kota's account?
那是孝多的帐号？
Huh?
什么？
I didn't know that.
我不知道
Four days ago, I found a letter in my bag on my way home from cram school.
四天前 我从补习班回家时 打开书包发现一封信
Here's the pudding a la mode.
这是法式布丁
Hang on.
请等一下
Please use this.
请用这个
"You cheated on the mock exam on June 5th."
“你在6月5日的模拟考作弊
"If you don't want to be exposed,
不想让别人知道的话
log in to Dropping Puzzle and keep paying for game items."
就登录《扔谜语》并持续充值
"Use the account below."
使用以下这个帐号”
It's Kota's ID and password.
这是孝多的帐号密码
Go ahead.
请用
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey, was there a security check when you paid for the items?
这个游戏要充值时 都不用确认什么吗？
Nothing after I logged in.
登录后无需密码
So, the credit card info was tied to the account.
所以信用卡资料是跟帐号绑在一起的
You followed the instructions without knowing the circumstances, right?
你搞不清楚状况 只是按照说明去做吧？
Yes.
对
So, you did do it.
这么说你真的做了
The cheating.
作弊
I failed the elementary school entrance exam, so this is it.
我小学考试不及格 所以就作弊了
I'm sorry!
对不起
You scared me. It's alright.
吓到我了 没事
Do you have any idea who sent you this letter?
你知道这封信可能是谁寄的吗？
No.
不知道
Will I be exposed?
不会说出去吧？
Don't worry. Let's forget about the cheating for now.
别担心 先不说作弊的事吧
Take your spoon and eat the pudding.
拿勺子吃你的布丁吧
The mock exam seating based on his statement.
根据他的陈述 模拟考的座位安排是这样的
It was for all classes and there were about 40 students.
全班都要接受模拟考 大约有40名学生
The examiner was Mr. Kondo and Ms. Fukase, the clerk.
监考人员是近藤老师 和行政人员深濑小姐
And Eiichi's seat is right at the front.
荣一同学的位置在最前面
It's hard to narrow down the culprit.
要锁定真凶也太困难了吧
-I'm back. -Good work.
-我回来了 -辛苦了
This is the client's call log.
这是委托人申请出来的通话记录
-Thank you. -Finally.
-谢谢 -终于来了
Well, it's no longer about refunds now.
现在的重点已经不是退款了
Oh, yeah.
对了
Ichigo pants.
草莓内裤
-What? -Huh?
-什么？
-Are you okay? -Huh?
-你是怎么了？
I can hear you. What about it?
我听到了 但你讲这个做什么？
That's the password for Kota's phone.
这是孝多手机的解锁密码
1582.
日文谐音是1582
It's wordplay of the year of the Honno-ji Incident.
刚好是本能寺之变那一年
He said Emiru knows this password.
他说绘美瑠知道这个密码
Yes, I know.
是 我知道
Kota felt sorry for you because your parents banned you from playing games
你很喜欢玩游戏 但你爸妈不准
and he let you play on his phone once after class.
孝多同情你 有一次下课就把手机借给你玩
That's when he told you the password. Correct?
就是这时候 他把密码告诉你 对吧？
Yes.
对
This password, Ichigo Pants or 1582, have you told it to anyone?
这个密码 草莓内裤的代号 你有告诉过任何人吗？
No, I never did.
没有 从来没有
I see.
这样啊
Oh, but…
不过…
Huh?
奇怪？
This call log.
通话记录这里
It's different from the call history I saw.
跟我先前看到的记录不一样
It wasn't on his phone.
手机上没有这一条
What?
什么？
That means someone intentionally deleted this call log.
也就是说 有人刻意删掉这个通话记录
Yeah, most likely.
应该是吧
You really do have an amazing memory.
羽男先生 你的记忆力真好
Here.
找到了
That number is for…
这个电话号码是…
This is Oba.
我是大庭
I need to check something.
有件事要请你立刻帮忙查
"Free phone consultation."
“免费电话咨询”
Thank you.
谢谢
Sorry to keep you waiting.
不好意思 让您久等了
We called you here to help us catch the culprit who stole Kota's wallet.
为了找出偷走孝多钱包的真凶 我们请大家过来帮忙
The real culprit will show up soon.
真凶很快就会现身
I told the culprit I won't expose the crime if he or she confesses here.
如果真凶愿意认罪 我就不会公开对方的罪行
Will we be able to help?
我们能帮上忙吗？
Sure. We just need you to testify about what you saw.
当然 只要你们作证 说出看到的事情就可以了
-Okay. -Yes.
-好
I'm nervous.
好紧张
Yeah.
对啊
Please take one.
请用吧
Those are bad choices.
你也太不会采购了吧
Why such random selections?
为什么都买不一样的？
Because people have different tastes.
有各种口味才好 大家才能挑到自己喜欢的
The point was to get them to relax.
重点是要让大家放松吧
It's hard to choose when there's only one of each.
一种只有一个 很难选的
What was better--
不然要买什么好？
Like normal tea and water.
普通的茶水就好
I researched children's favorite drinks and there they are.
我搜索小学生喜欢的饮料 买了排名最靠前的来
Tea or water was not listed.
茶和水根本不在排行榜上面
But look, no one is drinking it.
但你看 实际上就没有人要喝
-We'll take one. -Yes.
-我们会喝… -对
-Thank you. -I want this.
-我们不客气了 -我要这个
Everyone, sit over here.
大家要坐在位置上喝
Yes, sir.
好
I'll take something refreshing.
我要拿清新一点的
We got it!
出现了
I'll be taking this.
这个我先收回来
-Excuse me. -What?
-不好意思 -什么？
I said we gathered you here because we needed your help catching the culprit
模拟考那天 孝多的钱包被偷了
who stole Kota's wallet on the day of the mock exam, right?
为了抓到犯人 想请各位提供证词 我是这样说才请大家集合的
Such an incident did not happen.
不过这起事件并没有发生
What we really wanted to expose
我们真正想揪出来的
is the person who caused the 250,000-yen damage to Kota and his mother.
是让孝多和他妈妈 损失二十五万日圆的人
And that is…
也就是
you.
你
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Man, I got worried because you wouldn't touch the drinks.
天啊 你都不碰饮料 急死我了
It's your mistake to begin with.
还不是律师的错
We were supposed to hand them out.
原本要拿给大家的 结果放在桌上
-Hey, can we forget-- -What is this?
-这个不是现在的重点… -到底是怎样？
Emiru said…
绘美瑠说…
When she was unlocking Kota's smartphone,
她在解锁孝多的手机时
she may have said "Ichigo Pants" out loud.
可能不小心说出了“草莓内裤”
-That's Kota's. -I got his permission.
-那是孝多的手机 -他同意借我的
1582, Ichigo Pants.
草莓内裤
So…
换句话说
…she may have overheard…
你很可能在办公室
…Kota's password…
偷听到了孝多的
…in the office.
手机密码
If you know the password…
只要知道密码
…you can unlock the phone that are kept during class.
就可以在上课的时候解锁保管的手机
All that's left is to start the game.
再来只要打开游戏
Doropazu's ID and password can be displayed.
《扔谜》可以设定显示帐号密码
So, there's a possibility you used that to
你利用这件事来威胁荣一同学
blackmail Eiichi.
是有可能的
Assuming with just "a possibility" is--
怎么能光靠可能性来判断…
Since the possibility isn't zero, I did a little digging.
因为可能性不是零 所以我去做了一些调查
You have caused a similar incident at the cram school you previously worked at.
你在以前任职的补习班 也引起过类似的事件
These are the notes from the interview.
以下是我们去访问时的记录
When you were caught, you said you were raised by poorly educated parents
你被抓到时 说自己的爸妈教育程度不高
and they wanted you to work after high school.
一直叫你中学毕业就出来工作
Had you gone to a good university, you would've had a good life.
你若是能上个好大学 人生会很美好
That's why you wanted to drag down the kids who are taking entrance exams.
因此才会想要拖考生的后腿
You never apologized for it.
你从来没有道过歉
Ms. Fukase?
深濑小姐
You felt the same way again and committed the crime, right?
你又怀着同样的心情作案 对吧？
No.
错了
I wouldn't do such a thing.
我才不会做这样的事情
Ms. Fukase, let's talk about this.
深濑小姐 把话说清楚
Then, why are you running?
如果不是 为什么要逃？
The police are on this case.
警察已经在调查了
The blackmail letter has fingerpri--
恐吓信上采到了荣一同学以外的指纹
Don't touch me!
不要碰我
Why do I have to be arrested?
我为什么要被逮捕啊？
Why did you go after Kota?
你为什么要针对孝多同学？
He was whining that he wants to quit cram school but he can't.
他在抱怨不想上补习班了 却没办法如愿
So, I thought I'd make it happen.
我就想让他如愿吧
You're out of your mind.
你是有什么毛病？
Everyone here is a winner who won the parent-gacha, right?
各位都是赢得父母转蛋的胜利组吧
All my parents ever told me was to give up.
我爸妈只会叫我放弃
How pathetic.
太可悲了
Don't drag others down just because you're unhappy with your life.
不要因为对自己的人生不满意 就拖其他人下水
-Are you stupid? -L.E.!
-你是笨蛋吗？ -律伦
The world is unfair.
这个世界太不公平了
Fine, that's enough. I'm calling the police.
够了 我知道了 我请警察来
Hello. I'm Haneoka from Ushio Law Firm.
你好 我是潮法律律所的羽根冈
I only said it to let everyone here know
我是为了让你们知道
how blessed you all are.
自己有多幸运 才这么说的
There's no denying
确实
that everyone's life is different from the moment we're born.
人生会因为起跑线的不同 而有很大的差异
With an actual gacha capsule toy,
可是真实的转蛋
you have the right to exchange your item if it's defective.
如果抽到瑕疵品 可以依法要求更换
But for a parent-gacha, there's no law that allows an exchange
但是父母转蛋 就算你认为抽到瑕疵品
even if you think they're defective.
也没有法律可以让你更换
However, I don't think we should just accept the environment we're born into.
但我不认为 我们只能全盘接受自己出生的环境
Because horrible parents do exist.
因为很过分的爸妈真的存在
If that's the case,
如果是这样的话
I want you to speak up.
请大家一定要大声说出来
But…
不过…
I think most parents are doing their best to be a parent.
我想大部分的爸妈 都很努力要当个好爸妈
Aloha.
阿啰哈
Kota, today's lunch is minced meat on rice.
孝多 今天的午餐是绞肉盖饭
I wonder how much you can eat.
不知道你能吃多少
This much?
这样差不多吧？
-Let's eat. -I'll put it in the fridge, okay?
-我要开动了 -我装保鲜盒放冰箱
I know you don't like eggplants, but look.
我知道你不喜欢吃茄子 但你看
I noticed it!
我有发现啦
You can't taste the eggplant.
也吃不出茄子的味道吧
I can!
可以啦
There's miso soup too.
还有味噌汤
Most children are also
多数的孩子也想
trying their best as children to make their parents proud.
响应父母的期待 努力当个好小孩
Saying you won or lost…
这样的亲子关系
about such parent and child relationship…
用输赢来判断
What's the point?
有什么意义吗？
That's all.
我说完了
Hey, no. Don't run!
不行 不可以逃跑
Your sins are grave.
你的罪是很重的
Article 223 Clause 1 of the Penal Code, extortion against Eiichi is
你对荣一做的事触犯了 刑法第223条第一项的强制罪
up to three years of imprisonment.
可判处三年以下有期徒刑
Unauthorized login to Kota's account is also a violation.
擅自登入孝多的帐号 违反了不当访问禁止法
Up to three years in prison or a fine of up to one million yen.
可判处三年以下有期徒刑 或是100万日圆以下罚金
Additionally, the unauthorized use of a credit card is a computer fraud.
另外 盗刷信用卡触犯刑法 第246条第二项的电脑欺诈罪
You could be imprisoned for up to 10 years.
可判处十年以下有期徒刑
Considering the motive and the amount of money,
考量到动机和金额大小
it's quite possible you'll be facing a prison sentence.
判你入狱服刑是很有可能的
That leaves the 198,700 yen refund.
这样就剩下 十九万八千七百日圆的退款了
The refund, huh?
退款啊？
I'm out of ideas.
我没办法了
How about this?
这个办法怎么样？
I saw this on the Doropazu walkthrough website.
我在游戏攻略网站发现了这个
This game's specifications changed drastically 32 days ago, didn't it?
这个游戏在32天前进行了大幅改版
This is the current age verification screen.
这是现在的年龄确认屏幕
As you said,
如你所说
it asks, "Are you 18 years or older?" and the user answers with a yes or no.
它会问“是否已年满18岁” 请使用者回答“是”与“否”
On the other hand, this is the age verification screen before the change.
另一方面 这是改版前的年龄确认屏幕
This was being used until a while ago.
不久之前都还是这个屏幕
The age verification is listed within other statements
在许多注意事项中 列明了年龄确认的条目…
and the user answers whether they agree to the terms of use as a whole.
…使用者只回答是否同意 整体的使用规则
This is intended for use by minors,
明明就假设了会有未成年人使用…
but the age verification is listed in this tiny space while scrolling down
却要滑半天才会出现 这里记载了小小的年龄确认项
and it's hard to read.
很难看到
And the problem is…
问题是…
Here's the problem.
问题在于…
Kota Aida paid for game items 56 days ago.
相田孝多同学充值是在56天前
Meaning…
也就是说
it was during the use of this specification.
还是这个版本的时候
We believe that, in this regard, Doropazu may also be at fault
对此我方认为游戏公司有所疏失
and will assert the minor's right to rescind.
主张限制行为能力人的解约权
Of course, we're considering going to court.
当然 也不排除提告
We have good news for you today.
今天是来报告一个好消息
-The refund-- -Mr. Haneoka.
-关于退款… -羽根冈律师
Yes?
什么？
He told me earlier
他先前告诉我
that he paid for game items on purpose.
他是故意充值的
I know I've put you through so much already.
造成你们这么多麻烦 真的很抱歉
But we no longer want a refund.
不过我们已经不要求退款了
What? Are you sure?
什么？这样好吗？
It's a fair rule.
这是正当的规则
Society's rules may be so.
社会的规则或许是如此
But I'd like to follow our family's rules.
但请让我用我们家的规则来处理
I want Kota to take responsibility.
我想让孝多负起自己的责任
So, he'll be paying me back half of the cost from his monthly allowance.
充值的一半 由他每个月的零用钱当中扣除
The other half
另外一半
will be my punishment.
就当做我自己的惩罚
He won't be taking the exam either.
他也不参加考试了
Right?
对吧？
Can I ask you a question?
我可以问你一个问题吗？
In your call log,
通话记录上
there's a record of you calling a legal consultation service.
有一通从你的手机 打到法律咨询专线的记录
Huh?
什么？
But that call log was deleted from your phone.
但是你的手机没有留下这条记录
Why did you do that?
为什么要删掉？
What? You did that?
什么？是你做的吗？
You found that out too, huh?
连这个也发现了啊？
When I was searching for a way to quit cram school online,
我上网搜搜有什么办法不去补习班时
I found a case
查到了有考生
where a student who paid for game items got a refund.
因为未成年什么的 充值的钱可以退还的案件
I called a lawyer to ask about it.
我打电话去问律师
And I was told we'd usually get a refund. That's why I did it.
对方说基本上都会退钱 我才充值的
But I didn't want anyone to find that out. So I deleted it.
但我不想让人发现 就把记录删除了
What do you mean?
什么意思？
If we find out that he was calm enough to consult a lawyer,
如果被人发现他冷静地去咨询律师
his scenario, paying for game items due to exam stress, would fall apart.
因为考试压力而去给游戏充值 这种剧情说不通吧
It was a grand scenario in his own way.
他设定了这么宏大的剧情
To figure out how quit the cram school without troubling his mother.
怎么在不造成妈妈困扰的情况下 退出补习班
But actually, you still want to take the entrance exams, don't you?
但你其实没有不想参加考试吧？
Mom, you've been working so hard for me every day.
妈妈 你为了我每天这么辛苦
I said I want to take the entrance exam to make your life easier.
我本来是想让你过得更幸福 才说要参加考试的
But I had second thoughts because it's wearing you out.
但因为害你这么累 我就犹豫了
But if I told you that, you'd say, "Don't worry about me," right?
但如果我这么说 你一定会说“不要担心我”
So, I decided to go with exam stress.
所以我才想拿考试压力当借口
And yet, we couldn't get a refund.
结果不但拿不回退款
I caused you trouble.
还给你惹出麻烦
-Sorry. -Silly boy!
-对不起 -傻小子
You said you want to quit out of the blue.
你突然说不想考试了
I knew something was wrong.
我就觉得事有蹊跷
If you want to do it,
你想考的话
you can do it.
就去考吧
Yeah.
好
I hope I'm not being intrusive, but
希望我不会太过唐突
this is a list of benefits available for single mothers.
这是单亲妈妈能领到的福利清单
My mother was the same.
我的妈妈也是
She worked hard to support me because she didn't want me to give up anything
不希望我因为单亲家庭 就放弃任何想做的事
for the reason that she's a single parent.
非常拼命地工作要支持我
It still makes me feel regretful to think that I could've made her life easier
如果当时知道有这些规定 说不定就能让她轻松一点了
had I known these rules back then.
现在想起来还是觉得很遗憾
Thank you very much for everything.
真的很谢谢你们
The number of consultations about children paying for
儿童使用手机或家用游戏机
game items on smartphones and video games without parental consent
未经父母同意就充值的咨询案件
has been increasing…
不断增加…
INCREASING TROUBLE OF CHILDREN BILLING WITHOUT PARENTAL CONSENT
（儿童未经监护人同意 擅自充值的困扰快速增加）
Alright.
好了
How's my resume?
我的履历看起来怎么样？
Yeah…
这个嘛…
Oh, here.
请用
Could you read the self-introduction part?
你可以读一下自传的部分吗？
Sure.
好
"I was subjected to power harassment in my previous workplace
“我在先前的职场受到职权骚扰
and I'm still fighting this case."
现在仍在争取权益”
I think you can leave those things out.
这件事应该不用写上去吧
It's great to be honest, but don't you think
坦率是件好事 但你不觉得
it makes it harder to hire you?
这样写更难让人雇用你吗？
-Great advice! -Good luck.
-谢谢您的建议 -加油
Thank you.
好
What? Another complaint?
又有什么意见吗？
Adding gesture does make you look genius-ish.
加点小动作 看起来更像天才
I'll accept that.
这点我接受
It probably won't cause any trouble
可能也不会引起任何问题
and I've learned that you have your own way of doing things.
我了解到羽根冈律师有自己的作法
Oh, really?
这样吗？
So, like this.
所以 像这样
-My pose? -Yes.
-你说姿势吗？ -对
Like this? Hmm.
像这样？
Yes.
对
Don't I look like Piccolo doing the Special Beam Cannon?
看起来像不像 使出魔贯光杀炮的比克？
You do.
的确
That's no good then.
这样不太妙吧
Isn't there something more original?
有没有感觉更原创性的作法？
-Something else? -More creative.
-别的动作呢？ -更具独创性的
And also cool.
帅气的姿势
Delicate touch of the finger.
手指的感觉更纤细一点
The hand should be here.
手应该是这种感觉
Like I'm deep in thought.
在深思的时候
-Let me see. -Yes, that's it.
-让我看一下 -对…
What's wrong with fast movies?
快电影有什么问题吗？
I'll make him feel remorse.
我一定会让他好好反省
I spent ten years on it and this is it, huh?
累积十年的结果就是这样吗？
I should just give up?
难道不做任何努力就要放弃吗？
You're a genius.
你可是天才啊
He may not get a suspended sentence unless he changes that attitude.
他不改变态度的话 就争取不到缓刑
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo
字幕翻译：赤焰